<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friedrich Rieber</title>
    <description>This Friedrich Rieber&#39;s personal Webpage  Created with Jekyll
</description>
    <link>frizr.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="frizr.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:34:56 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:34:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenCV Project PLuTO</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;general&quot;&gt;General&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLuTO (Puck Lokalisierung und Tracking mit OpenCv) German for “Puck Localisation and Tracking with OpenCV” is a Software designed for Physik Students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At TU Berlin Physik Students try to simulate Particels in a gas with hockey like pucks on a air table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software tries to help the Students with tracking the pucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-1&quot;&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software was developed during the “Mathesis Labor” Course from the Technical University Berlin in a Group of about 15 people at the start and was finished, like a lot of group projects, by 5 remaining Students. This high drop out Rate can be explained by the voluntary status of the lab. Mathesis is one of many labs in the “MINTgrün Orientierungsstudium” which is a 2 Semester orientation study direction at the Technical University of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Goals for this Software were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning OpenCV (Open Computer Vision Library)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;learning Tkinter (Gui Library)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;producing a tool which can track pucks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning a little bit machine learning for detection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning to work in a group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-results&quot;&gt;Final Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of this group project there were only a fraction of the persons still working on it but we still managed to get something working with a somewhat nice looking GUI put together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-conclusion&quot;&gt;Personal conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to python, OpenCV, bash scripting, azure server handling and git on the technical site i learned a lot of how working in a bigger group works and how hard it is to finish a project and how important communication is. Overall i would say the Mathesis Lab was a total succes although our finished Product is not the thing we dreamed of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software has yet to be used, the idea of physics student using this software was hypothetical but could have become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ressources&quot;&gt;Ressources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pluto-development-team/puck-tracker-pluto&quot;&gt;Github Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdfs/pluto.pdf&quot;&gt;Presentation in German&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pictures/detection_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;result of the detection algorithm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pictures/gui_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The landing Page of the gui&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friedrich Rieber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>frizr.github.io/projects/2018/08/29/OpenCV-Project-PLuTo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">frizr.github.io/projects/2018/08/29/OpenCV-Project-PLuTo.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Blog Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first Blog Post. Testing out Jekylls Static Site Builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Goal with this Blog is to document my personal Projects, which are listed on my GitHub Account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that some tipps and tricks about multiple Topics and other Projects which are not big enough to get their own repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friedrich Rieber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 22:34:10 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>frizr.github.io/general/2018/08/28/first-blog-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">frizr.github.io/general/2018/08/28/first-blog-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
